NARRATOR: Previously on The Vampire Diaries:
Travelers are about to make their move. Their leader, Markos, is here.
MARKOS: The blood of the doppelgangers can undo the witch's curse...
that prevents us from finding a home. We can break that curse.
- Where the hell am I? - Welcome back, Julian.
You passengered into a hybrid.
SHEILA: Something's wrong over here, Bonnie.
Whatever the Travelers did, whoever managed to get through...
it's got the witches scared.
What about you? Any pretty girls?
ENZO: Actually, there was one. Her name was Maggie.
Seventy years of captivity and she was the face that I clung onto.
I didn't know she was your Maggie.
[ENZO GRUNTING]
You won't stop until you kill Damon.
It'll be a sweet piece of revenge when Damon finds out you killed his best friend.
STEFAN: Damon thinks that Enzo left town.
We need to keep it that way.
MARIA: Wake up, babe.
Missed you.
Julian. Is it still you?
Yeah.
Bad dream.
What were you saying?
Mm.
Oh.
Look, I'm always up for a little bit of kink but...
Heh. Markos' orders. I put them on you as soon as you fell asleep.
You passengered in a hybrid.
Can't risk him popping out.
Pecs are a plus.
[MOANS]
- But excess security is a minus. MAN: Maria.
We're on the move.
Looks like this is gonna have to wait.
- Where are we going? - To the next camp.
Which will hopefully be our last camp.
Markos is ready to do the spell.
- He's taken the doppelgangers. - Today?
As soon as we're out of here.
Soon we can actually have a home.
And I can finally have a closet.
Better yet two closets. One for clothes and one for shoes.
[YELLING AND GRUNTING]
Julian.
Babe, what's wrong?
Open your eyes.
[PANTING]
Oh, my God. You're not...
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[BONES CRACKING AND TYLER GRUNTING]
[TYLER CONTINUES GRUNTING]
I need help! Somebody!
[GRUNTING STOPS]
[TYLER GROWLS THEN MARIA SCREAMS]
[LUKE CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[IN ENGLISH] That's not helping.
You've been failing for an hour, wonder twin...
so at this point I can't imagine it's hurting.
Damon, I know you're out a friend but, uh, I'm not sure this guy's the best replacement.
I don't think this guy's the best anything if his locator-spell skills are any indication.
Yo. Where's your sister?
She's tired of being almost murdered.
Look, I can find any person anywhere on the planet.
Okay? There's just something weird with your friend Enzo. I can't get a read.
Enzo.
- Didn't he, uh, go to Cape Horn? - He flipped his humanity switch.
There should have been a body count all the way to the airport.
Ah.
- Why are you looking for him? - Gee, I don't know, Stefan.
A vampire with no humanity who wants me dead for killing his girl. Hmm.
Well, maybe he hired a witch to block whatever Luke's doing.
- Is that possible? LUKE: A cloaking spell?
- I guess. - Would mean that he doesn't wanna be found.
So, uh, why don't you just drop it?
We have a problem.
Markos turned Sloan into a vampire, had her drink doppelganger blood...
and after some chanty ritual thing, she turned human again.
- He cured her? - He cured her to death.
Blood took her vampirism. Left her in the state she was before she turned.
- That state being dead. Got it. - So it kills vampires.
- What's the spell mean for the witches? - No one cares. Keep going.
They feel if they get rid of all magic, they'll break some lame-ass witch curse.
Markos said they can't settle without evoking earthquakes or hellfire.
They break that curse, they move on in to Mystic Falls.
And come after Elena and me today.
- As in now. DAMON: Oh, well.
Markos had a good week in the land of the living.
- Now, where is he so I can kill him? - No idea.
- They were moving camp. - Our friend Luke here...
is an alleged genius at locator spells.
Travelers are always moving. They're impossible to track.
They'll find Stefan and Elena before we can find them.
What about one of those locator spell blocker deals?
Is that simple enough for you?
If both doppelgangers are in the same place, yeah.
Perfect. You avoid the entire Czech language, figure out how to finds Markos.
How am I supposed to do that?
Well, you have a Traveler inside of you.
I have probably misplaced faith that you'll figure it out.
You and I and our ex-girlfriend are gonna go on a little secret trip.
Sounds great.
ELENA: This is a terrible idea.
STEFAN: Well, what did you want me to say?
"No, Damon, it'll be awkward to have the three of us confined to Caroline's dad's cabin...
because I killed your best friend and Elena is keeping it a secret for me"?
We should have told him.
Look, I don't trust that he'd be able to hold it together.
Because Enzo's dead or because you killed him?
Either. Both. I don't know. Either way.
CAROLINE: Good news.
So we don't have to be invited in. Heh.
Which is actually super sad if you think about it.
STEFAN: Mm.
- Am I interrupting something? - No, no, we're just, um...
Uh, unpacking. We're unpacking.
Uh, there you go.
Okay.
[CAROLINE CHUCKLES]
[ELENA SIGHS]
So where's Damon now?
- Helping Luke set up. - Helping Luke or avoiding me?
- Really don't think he wants to be around you? - Well, he said:
"I don't wanna hear your voice and I don't wanna see your face."
Because it's too hard for him.
Who do you think brought you home last night?
- Really? - Oh, yeah.
- Tucked you in. ELENA: That was an extreme circumstance.
Enzo almost killed me.
Probably read you a nice little bedtime story.
Stop it. Heh. You're the least-helpful person I know.
For a couple of targets, you two seem to be taking this in stride.
Yeah, well, you know...
a tribe of, uh, ancient wanna-be witches wanna drain of us our blood...
and, uh, eliminate supernatural beings. I've had worse.
For some reason, I thought that would feel better.
Cozy.
Yeah, Caroline used to invite me here before her parents split.
Her dad could tell a pretty good ghost story.
I hope that dickwad's spirit isn't floating around anywhere.
- Have a little respect for the dead. - I respect that he's dead.
How about that?
I'm supposed to be avoiding you.
- Is that still what you want? - Yes.
No.
I don't know.
Well, Luke did the cloaking spell. Stefan and Caroline are here so we should be good.
- But if it's too hard for you... - Are you kicking me out?
Yes. No. I don't know.
I'm really sorry Enzo came after you.
That was my fault. He was hurt.
It's not a big deal.
It is a big deal. He almost killed you, Elena.
I'm gonna hunt his ass down, I'm gonna whip some sense into him.
I'm gonna make him apologize in person, okay?
- What? - Hmm? No, nothing. I just, uh...
I remembered Stefan asked me to help him bring some firewood in.
So I'll be right back.
What?
What are we gonna do about the Other Side slipping off into oblivion and you with it?
We have the dorm to ourselves for an entire weekend and you wanna talk logistics?
I would enjoy this weekend a whole lot more if I knew we were able to keep doing it.
I told you Liv is working on a spell to keep me here.
[SIGHS]
[CELL PHONE BUZZES]
- Oh. Another secret bro meeting? - No more secrets, remember?
Tyler's back.
We should get over there.
Let me grab my stuff.
[SIGHS]
SHEILA: Please.
Tell me more about this special spell that your friend Liv has concocted.
I know I shouldn't lie.
He deserves the truth, Bonnie. It's not getting any better over here.
People are getting swept away.
And when this place goes, you are going with it.
I know I have to tell him. I just need a few more days with him before...
How did you do that?
How did you move that? You can't move things from the Other Side.
- That doesn't happen. - That's what I'm trying to tell you.
This place is falling apart. Tell him. Soon.
False hope doesn't protect him.
It protects you.
- I lied to his face. - Yeah, I know.
You know what? Think of all the times he's lied to you.
Call it a freebie.
Glad you two find my death so amusing.
Sorry that you have to go through this.
You're sorry for that? Glad we've got our priorities straight.
I know that we're doing this for Damon but it still just sucks.
Elena, this is exactly what Enzo wanted. He wanted the blood to be on my hands.
I refuse to give him the satisfaction of feeling guilty.
You think Damon is just gonna forget and move on?
He's done it before.
Let's get out of here.
Now, there's an interesting development.
Hey. Munchy, that's enough for you.
Shh. I'm thinking.
Hey-
- "Area 51 - Stop.
"JFK assassination." What the hell is that?
You're ruining the game.
- What game? - Charades.
Our theme is secrets that people think that they're getting away with.
Well, Meryl Streep, I'd love to know how we're gonna act out "Watergate."
- Well, I'm sure Team Stelena will figure it out. - A, you just implied that I was on your team.
Two, you just gave me that judgey little hinty voice.
So, what am I missing?
It's probably nothing.
Uh...
Speak.
[CAROLINE SIGHS]
Well, don't you think that Stefan and Elena have been a little... you know.
- No, clearly, I don't. - Secretive?
I caught them being all hushed and whispery at the car.
Now they're getting wood out of the shed together...
which apparently takes 20 minutes.
You know, now that you mention it...
Elena got all cagey when I brought up Enzo.
No, no, I'm not talking about Enzo. I'm talking about Stefan and Elena.
- How much have you had to drink? - Come on.
She's single now, you two are on the outs.
ELENA: Cocktails. Good call. - I'll, uh, make a fire.
I'll help. Ahem.
Let the games begin.
[SIGHS]
When we planned our romantic day together, I wasn't picturing you, me and two other guys.
Trust me, neither was I.
One part wolfsbane, one part vervain.
Altogether the dumbest idea...
- ...either of you have ever had. - Don't look at me. This is all Ty.
These should hold.
- Let's do this. - Not to be the only girl here...
but I can't watch this.
I'm gonna go upstairs.
[MATT SIGHS]
Ty, once this guy pops out, we have no idea when you'll come back again.
Some freak is inside my body. He took over my life.
God only knows what he's got planned for me. So unless you've got any better ideas...
this is what we're doing.
Okay, let's do this.
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GASPS]
Who are you? Where am I?
Where's Markos?
Go to hell.
To answer your question, my name is Matt, and you, Julian, are inside my best friend...
a. k.a., your own personal hell.
[GRUNTING]
[JULIAN YELLS]
Maria.
Julian's your husband. Why didn't you realize he wasn't in control of the body?
He'd only been called out for a few hours. I've never seen a host re-emerge so quickly.
[SCOFFS]
You've never seen a hybrid before either. Find him.
And make him permanent.
As for the rest of you...
I see a lot of walking when I should be hearing chanting.
Find me the doppelgangers.
[UPBEAT POP MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Uh, okay, uh, think. Uh, ponder.
Uh, brain.
Uh, I don't know. Um...
- Uh, skull. All right. Skull. Skull. - Yes.
Okay, uh, limb. Joints. Uh, bones.
Bone. Bone. Skull and bones.
- Yeah. - Skull and bones.
You got it.
- Five-zero. Five-zero. ELENA: Ha, ha.
- Five-zip. - Ha, ha.
Okay, let's play a game called Never Have I Ever, hmm?
- Ah. I don't think I'm drunk enough. - Oh, come on, it'll be fun.
- Come on, it'll be fun. - I'll go first.
Never have I ever died.
Pfft. Cheers to that one.
- Cheers. STEFAN: Oh, okay, um...
Never have I ever been, um, possessed by my evil doppelganger.
Pfft. Mean.
[ELENA CHUCKLES]
Never have I ever been fooled by my evil doppelganger...
while she was pretending to be me. STEFAN: Ah.
- Low blow. - Tough, but fair.
- Never have I ever kissed a Salvatore brother. STEFAN: Hmm.
ELENA: Mm-hm.
Today.
- So are you gonna drink or...? - Are you implying something?
Well, I'm gonna get another round.
- Um, does anybody...? - Never have I ever lied about where Enzo is.
- Okay, what is going on? - Nothing, obviously.
- Nobody is drinking. - Clearly, you know the rules of the game, right?
If you lied, you drink.
Oh, no, I understand the rules.
This just got weird.
I'm officially buzzed, so I'm gonna, ahem, go and get ready for bed.
Well, I could certainly use another round.
Ah.
Avoiding, are we?
Nothing a hot bath won't fix.
Wash the guilt straight down the drain.
ELENA: Damon!
DAMON: Elena!
[ELENA GASPS THEN PANTS]
Come here. Hold on. What happened?
- There was someone in here. - Who?
[PANTING]
I don't know. I didn't see anyone.
But I could feel someone pushing me under the water.
Okay. I'd blame it on the spirit of Bill Forbes, but I don't think you're his type.
Besides, why would a ghost be targeting you?
Hey-
Elena.
- Damon. - What? Hey.
[GRUNTING]
MATT: There's plenty more where that came from.
Where's Markos?
What does it matter to you?
He wants to kill my sister. I wanna stop him.
[CHUCKLING]
JULIAN: You're a fool.
Markos destroyed your only weapon against passengers like me.
And there's no way you'd kill your best friend.
[JULIAN GRUNTING]
You're right. I don't plan on killing you. But I do plan on getting my answers.
Where is Markos?
[PANTING]
[GRUNTING]
Stop!
I can't tell you where Markos is because I don't know.
- But I can tell you where my body is. - Why do we care?
Because Markos doesn't like problems.
And your boy escaping camp means he's Markos' problem.
- So? - So knowing Markos...
he's gonna wanna get rid of Tyler for good by making this my body.
Permanently.
Stefan, hey. Remind me why I passed on the cloaking spell party again?
Well, it's not exactly a relaxing getaway.
Are things getting worse on the Other Side?
- Why? - Because something attacked Elena.
Is it possible that someone over there could physically affect this plane?
Actually, yeah.
My grams knocked a lamp right off my desk today.
I doubt it's easy, but if someone were emotional enough...
- Enzo. CAROLINE: Enzo's dead?
Yeah. I, um...
I killed him.
[SIGHS]
So my powers of deduction really suck.
- Why didn't you say anything? - Because it's complicated.
Enter the complication.
Enzo's dead. You killed him. Elena told me.
- So you didn't know, either? - Nope.
- And their secret really was about Enzo. - Yep.
You guys think we could, urn, talk about this some other time?
By all means, brother, at your convenience.
Listen, the Other Side is falling apart. It's allowing Enzo to mess with us.
Enzo.
You in here?
- I don't reckon I'd miss this. - Because knock it off.
CAROLINE: It doesn't make any sense.
If Enzo wanted to kill Elena, drowning her wouldn't have worked.
Smart girl. I see why you like her so much.
- Maybe he's trying to scare us. ENZO: Warmer.
Come on. You've almost got it. What is Enzo up to?
Drowning Elena was just a distraction.
He figured out a way to kill us all in one fell swoop.
Did I mention that I missed you?
Ugh. Crap.
STEFAN: Where's Luke? DAMON: Who knows?
We better find him before the Travelers find us.
[TRAVELERS CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[ALL CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[IN ENGLISH] Stop.
I found them.
- Luke! - Luke! Where are you?
Maybe Luke...
- You're upset. - I'm not upset. Just looking for Luke.
You know, Luke who was here to protect you and Stefan.
Luke who's now missing because you and Stefan lied about where Enzo was.
And now the Travelers can find you and wipe us all off the face of the earth.
- I worried that if Damon found out... - He'd flip out?
And spiral, and kill a bunch of innocent people? Yeah, I get that.
I, however, am not Damon.
So the fact that you lied to me about it makes less sense.
I didn't wanna put you in an awkward position.
Because it wasn't awkward when I accused you and Stefan of being makeout buddies again?
Actually, yes, it was.
Where did that even come from?
I have no idea.
- Well, are you over it? - Yes.
Good. Now let's go find Luke.
- You need to know why I lied to you. - Nope, I don't.
- Damon, come on. - Just cut to the chase, Stefan.
I'm not in a "hash-out-our-differences" mood.
Yes, I'm pissed you killed Enzo. I'm even more pissed that you two lied about it.
If I was in your shoes, I would've done it too, except I would've done it months ago.
- So the fact that you took this long... - He was your friend.
Yes, Stefan, he was my friend.
Which is why I, above anyone else, should've known that he was dead.
Let's just find the stupid witch.
[BONNIE SIGHS]
Of course the creepy Travelers are hiding their bodies in creepy caves.
Try to think of them as romantic Travelers in romantic caves...
since we're technically still on our date weekend.
Right.
[BONNIE SIGHS]
Oh, my God.
All these Travelers are passengered inside people in Mystic Falls?
I take it back. This is creepy.
DAMON'. What'd you think I was gonna do?
What are you talking about?
When I found out Enzo was dead. Go on a rampage?
Slaughter a bunch of innocent people? What'd you think I was gonna do?
Hate me.
I thought you would, uh, hate me.
[THUD NEARBY]
[WOOD CREAKING]
You hear that?
Yeah. Come on.
- He's barely breathing. - Why the hell would Enzo dump him here?
I don't know.
[SNIFFING]
Smell that?
Grab him. Let's go.
[STEFAN GRUNTING]
Dick move, Enzo.
[CREAKING]
[GRUNTING]
- If only this wasn't totally avoidable. - Really? Now you're doing I-told-you-so's?
This isn't gonna stop, Stefan. I killed his girl. You killed him.
He's right. I like poetic justice.
Damon Salvatore and his murderous brother die a fiery death.
Are you listening to me, Enzo?
Is that a yes or a no?
I can bring you back.
Bonnie came back. Markos came back. I'll find a way.
But this has to stop.
How do you think you're able to do all this stuff?
The Other Side's falling apart, Enzo.
So you could either help me, or you could blink out of existence.
It's your choice.
[GRUNTING]
Go, Stefan. Get Luke out of here.
He's the only one that could hide you and Elena.
[DAMON GROANING]
Ste'? an .
Go, now!
Come on.
Go on.
Don't let me down again.
[SIGHS]
- You sure Julian has an eagle tattoo? - That's what he said.
I'm pretty sure that's a dove.
Or a really cute eagle.
Moving on.
[BONNIE SIGHS]
I'm sorry. This is the worst date ever.
We're together. In a cave of semi-conscious Travelers who wanna take over our town.
But it could be worse, right?
Right. It could be.
[TRAVELERS CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GASPING]
Jeremy? Jeremy!
He may be a Hunter, but you'd be surprised at how easy it is to restrict a man's airways.
Please stop.
[TRAVELERS CONTINUE CHANTING]
Stop!
Jeremy. Jeremy.
STEFAN: Feeling okay?
[LUKE CHUCKLES]
Liv and I should've killed you.
Yeah, well, you didn't, and, uh, I don't understand why, but thank you.
Yeah, let's just say...
my family's pretty screwed up.
Not a whole lot of compassion.
You guys are different. You protect each other.
We still need you to protect us, so why don't you get your stuff...
- ...and, uh, we can get the hell out of here. - Yeah.
I guess Enzo bought it.
Bought what?
Bring him back. How do you plan on doing that?
Markos found his way back. It's not impossible.
Unless you want him terrorizing us for the rest of eternity.
Not particularly.
Mm-mm.
Uh, look, I know that...
[STEFAN GRUNTS]
I had to do that. For Enzo.
It's the last time you'll hear about it from me.
ELENA: Damon.
- What do you mean, you lost Julian's body? BONNIE: You-slash-he was right.
The Travelers wanted it.
But we'll find it. We just need to figure out where they went.
Hold on. What do they need his body for?
Guys, talk to me. Why did they take it?
[GRUNTS]
What are they doing here? This is our home. We can't let them take over.
They won't. I got it handled. I promise.
- Unh! - Ty, what's wrong?
I'm seeing things.
[GRUNTS]
- This body's incredible. - Don't get used to it.
[GRUNTING AND YELLING]
- Tyler, talk to us. - I don't know what's happening.
It's like I'm seeing his life.
[CONTINUES GRUNTING AND YELLING]
Oh, my God.
[ALL CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
They started the spell to make Julian permanent.
[ALL CONTINUE CHANTING]
[PANTING]
Make it stop. Make it stop!
[TYLER PANTING]
Tyler.
[GASPS THEN PANTS]
I take it you didn't find my body.
Never have I ever...
had a ghost try to burn me alive.
Drink.
Come on. Car's packed. We gotta get out of here.
We're friends, right?
We tell each other things, trust each other.
Caroline, it's not because I didn't trust you.
It's just that you trust Elena more. I get it. Of course you would.
Still sucks to be left out of the loop, you know?
If it makes you feel any better, there are things I tell you that I don't tell her.
- Like what? - Like, you have dirt on your cheek.
[CHUCKLES]
And, look, maybe I didn't want you to know that I killed Enzo.
- Why? - Because I know you...
and I know you guys had that weird little chemistry thing going on.
Oh, please. You're delusional.
I didn't want you to think any less of me.
[SIGHS]
I'll, uh, meet you over by the car when you're done.
- Hey. - Hey, we're leaving. Pack your stuff.
I will. I just came out to see how you were doing.
I'm in a hurry. You should be too. The Travelers can find us.
- So that's it? We're not gonna talk about this? - What's there to talk about?
- I'm sorry that I lied to you. - I don't care that you lied. Really.
Okay, I'm confused. Why are you being like this?
Because you were right, Elena.
You wanted to protect me so I wouldn't spiral.
Because if I spiraled, then it would prove that we shouldn't be together.
But I didn't spiral.
Despite every nerve in my body wanting to break something or hurt someone...
or do all the wrong things for all the right reasons...
I'm holding it together the best I can...
for you.
- But you're still mad at me. - Of course I'm still mad at you.
Because being around you drives me nuts.
And not being around you drives me nuts.
Okay, now I'm really confused.
What was that for?
Because I've had a really crappy day.
And I needed it.
[GRUNTING]
[TRAVELERS CHANTING]
[GASPS]
[English - US - SDH]